Ryan Pratama

ryanpratama.dev@gmail.com • +62-812-1042-5333 • linkedin.com/in/ryanpratama14 • ryanpratama.tech

SUMMARY

Experienced Software Engineer specializing in front-end development. Skilled in creating high-quality solutions tailored to client requirements, with a strong commitment to staying updated on industry trends and emerging technologies.

EXPERIENCE

PT Nutech Integrasi

Jakarta, Indonesia

Aug 2023 – Present

Front-end Engineer

- Developed CEISA 4.0, a web app for the Indonesian Directorate General of Customs and Excise, impacting 5000+ users.
- Created 25+ document formats and implemented PDF/XLSX rendering using React-pdf, jsPDF and ExcelJS.
- Ensured app quality with comprehensive testing: unit, integration, and end-to-end.
- Implemented seamless integration of RESTful APIs using Axios.
- Built fully responsive user interfaces primarily with Ant Design.
- Collaborated with UI/UX designers to implement visually compelling and intuitive interfaces.
- Worked with cross-functional teams, including back-end and QA engineers.
- Maintained regular and effective communication with system analysts.
- Utilized Git and Jira for prioritizing enhancements and bug fixes.
- Created documentation, aiding stakeholder understanding and future maintenance.

faoTech

*Remote*Sep 2022 – Aug 2023

Full-stack Engineer

Managed a front and team of 2 to 3 angineers agrees 3 projects.

- Managed a front-end team of 2 to 3 engineers across 3 projects.
- Built responsive web apps compatible across devices, integrating loading animations.
- Implemented essential authorization features like login, registration, and account recovery.
- Collaborated with UI/UX designers to create visually compelling user interfaces.
- Integrated internationalization support with i18next framework.
- Spearheaded back-end development, including API development, server-side logic, and database management.
- Proficient in CRUD operations and optimized RESTful API endpoints.
- Maintained comprehensive documentation to facilitate understanding with stakeholders.
- Provided ongoing maintenance and support for applications.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Libraries & Frameworks: Next.js, React, React Native, Node.js, Express.js, Hono, tRPC, Zod, Yup, Prisma, i18next,
 TanStack Query, Axios, Redux Toolkit, Zustand, Tailwind CSS, shaden/ui, Ant Design, MUI, styled-components, Framer
 Motion, React-pdf, jsPDF, ExcelJS.
- Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL.
- Tools & Platforms: Git, GitHub, Swagger, Postman, Vite, Vercel, Netlify, Firebase, Jira, Trello, Slack, Figma, Miro, Canva.

EDUCATION

Kazan (Volga region) Federal University | Institute of Management, Economics and Finance Bachelor's degree, Management

Kazan, Russia

Sep 2019 - Jun 2023

LANGUAGES

- Indonesian (native)
- Russian (professional)
- English (professional)
- Japanese (limited working)

CERTIFICATES

- N3, Japanese-Language Proficiency Test The Japan Foundation (Jul 2024)
- JavaScript (Intermediate) HackerRank (Jun 2024)

履歴書

2024年 8月 29日現在

ふりがな	ライアン・プラタマ				
氏 名	RYAN PRATAMA				
国籍	インドネシア	生年月日(年齢)	2000年7月14日生(満 23歳)	性別男・女	
ふりがな				電話 +62-812-1042-5333	
18/2-50	〒 13230			メールアドレス	
現住所	JL. RAWA JAYA I NO. 8, PISANGAN TIMUR, PULO GADUNG, JAKARTA TIMUR, INDONESIA			ryanpratama.dev@gmail.com	
ふりがな				電話	
	〒 42314 (現住所以外に連絡を希望する場合のみ記入)			メールアドレス	
連絡先	JL. KH ATIM II NO. 11L, MUARA CIUJUNG TIMUR, RANGKASBITUNG, BANTEN, INDONESIA			x=\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\	

年	月	学 歴・職 歴(各別にまとめて書く)		
		学歴		
2019	9	ロシア カザン(沿ヴォルガ)連邦大学 経営経済金融研究所 入学		
2023	6	ロシア カザン(沿ヴォルガ)連邦大学 経営経済金融研究所 卒業		
		ТЙ		
		職歴		
2022	9	FAOTECH 入社		
		ソフトウェア開発事業部 フルスタックエンジニア		
2023	8	一身上の都合により退社		
2023	8	PT NUTECH INTEGRASI 入社		
	}	ITソリューション事業部 フロントエンドエンジニア		
		現在に至る		
		٦KI		

1. 鉛筆以外の黒又は青の筆記具で記入。 2. 数字はアラビア数字で、文字はくずさず正確に書く。 記入上の注意 3. ※印のところは、該当するものを○で囲む。

年	月	学 歴・職 歴(各別にまとめて書く)		
••••••					
••••••					
			•••••		
		,			
年	月	免許 · 資格			
2024	7	日本語能力試験 N3 合格			
2024	6	HackerRank JavaScript (Intermediate)			
••••••					
		3	/A #1 ## 00		
フロントエ	ンド開発に	特技、自己PRなど 「重点を置いたソフトウェア エンジニアリングの経験が約 2	通勤時間		
			約 時間 分		
つせた高品	質のソリコ	Lーションを作成するスキルがあります。IT	扶養家族(配偶者を除く)		
プロフェッ	ショナルと	として豊富な経験があり、それを御社に提供したいと考えています。	0 人		
		<u> </u>	配偶者 配偶者の扶養義務		
			有・(無) 有・(無)		
		★ みゃらきつつ 488 / は・/- 4人が以 「助け手 並びかけも日 並びかり フェルノ・コンティング・ウ	94\		
		本人希望記入欄(特に給料・職種・勤務時間・勤務地・その他についての希望	望なとかめれば記入)		
国および	責社の規定	に従います。			

職務経歴書

2024年8月29日

氏名:ライアン プラタマ

■職務要約

大学の最終年に、スタートアップ企業でソフトウェアエンジニアとしてのキャリアをスタートしました。入社後4ヶ月で、フロントエンドエンジニアチームリーダーに昇進し、3人の開発者チームを管理しました。約1年後、より大規模なソフトウェア企業に移り、スタートアップと大手テック企業の両方の環境における洞察を得ました。

■職務経歴の概要

● 2023 年 8 月~現在 PT NUTECH INTEGRASI

● 2022 年 9 月~2023 年 8 月 FAOTECH

■活かせる経験・知識

- 約2名~5名規模のフロントエンドチームリーダーを経験
- ・顧客へのヒアリングから要件定義、開発までの経験
- TypeScript、React、現代のフレームワークによるアプリケーションの開発
- 外国語での就業経験:ロシア語と英語

■テクニカルスキル

- OS: Windows, macOS
- 開発言語: TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- フレームワーク: Next. js, React, React Native, Node. js, Express. js, Hono, tRPC, Zod, Yup, Prisma, i18next, TanStack Query, Axios, Redux Toolkit, Zustand, Tailwind CSS, shadcn/ui, Ant Design, MUI, styled-components, Framer Motion, React-pdf, jsPDF, ExcelJS.
- Tools & Platforms: Git, Swagger, Postman, Vite, Vercel, Jira, Trello, Figma.
- DB: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL.

■職務経歴

2023年8月~現在 PT NUTECH INTEGRASI

事業内容:ソフトウェアの受託開発 従業員数:約 400 名 所属:IT ソリューション事業部

期間	プロジェクト内容	環境	メンバー/役割
2023年8月	【プロジェクト名】CEISA 4.0	React, JavaScript,	9人
~	【プロジェクト概要】インドネシア税関総局向けの Web アプリ。	TypeScript, Ant	フロントエンド
現在	G2G、B2G、B2B のやり取り全体の統合を容易にすることで、税関業	Design, Git,	チームリーダー
	務を最適化することを目的としている。	Axios, Chart.js,	
	【担当フェーズ】要件定義、詳細設計、開発、テスト、運用保守	ExcelJS, js-PDF,	
	【業務内容】	React-pdf,	
	・ユーザー情報管理、認証システムの設計、開発	Postman, Jira,	
	・WEBの設計、開発、テスト、リリース、メンテナンス	Figma	
	・PDF、XLSX 形式のレンダリング		

フロントエンドチームリーダーとして、クライアントへ様々な提案	
を行い、複数の機能が採用をされました。	

2022年9月~2023年8月 FAOTECH

事業内容:ソフトウェアの受託開発 従業員数:約8名 所属:ソフトウェア開発事業部

期間	プロジェクト内容	環境	メンバー/役割
2023年6月	【プロジェクト名】HEBRONSTAR	React, JavaScript,	5人
~	【プロジェクト概要】CMS、キャリアマイクロサイト、管理ダッシ	TypeScript,	フロントエンド
2023年8月	ュボード、ランディングページの開発、求人の促進、候補者の応募	Express. js,	チームリーダー
	と運営の管理。	Node.js, Tailwind	
	【担当フェーズ】要件定義、詳細設計、開発、テスト、運用保守	CSS, Git, Axios,	
	【業務内容】	TanStack Query,	
	・ユーザー情報管理、認証システムの設計、開発	i18next, Zod,	
	・WEBの設計、開発、テスト、リリース、メンテナンス	Redux Toolkit,	
	・API の統合、開発	Swagger, Postman,	
	・多言語サポート開発	Jira, Trello,	
	・SEO 最適化	Figma, PostgreSQL	
2023年2月	【プロジェクト名】TURUNTANGAN	React, JavaScript,	5人
~	【プロジェクト概要】CMS、管理ダッシュボード、ランディングペ	TypeScript,	フロントエンド
2023年5月	ージ、ボランティア登録とネットワーク、ブログの開発。	Express. js,	チームリーダー
	【担当フェーズ】要件定義、詳細設計、開発、テスト、運用保守	Node.js, Tailwind	
	【業務内容】	CSS, Ant Design,	
	・ユーザー情報管理、認証システムの設計、開発	Git, Axios,	
	・WEBの設計、開発、テスト、リリース、メンテナンス	Chart.js, Redux	
	・API の統合、開発	Toolkit, Swagger,	
	・SEO 最適化	Postman, Jira,	
		Trello, Figma,	
		PostgreSQL	
2022年11月	【プロジェクト名】BELINSKY STUDIO	React, JavaScript,	4 人
~	【プロジェクト概要】管理ダッシュボード、ランディング ペー	TypeScript,	フロントエンド
2023年1月	ジ、連絡先ページの開発。	Tailwind CSS, Ant	チームリーダー
	【担当フェーズ】要件定義、詳細設計、開発、テスト、運用保守	Design, Git, Jira,	
	【業務内容】	Trello, Figma	
	・WEBの設計、開発、テスト、リリース、メンテナンス		
	・SEO 最適化		
2022年9月	【プロジェクト名】SINERGY PERDANA MANDIRI	React, JavaScript,	4人
~	【プロジェクト概要】ランディングページ、会社の製品情報、連絡	TypeScript,	メンバー
2023年10月	先ページの開発。	Tailwind CSS,	
	【担当フェーズ】詳細設計、開発、テスト、運用保守	Framer Motion,	
	【業務内容】	Git, Jira, Trello,	
	・WEBの設計、開発、テスト、リリース、メンテナンス	Figma	
	・SEO 最適化		

■資格・語学

・インドネシア語 : 母国語

・日本語 : 日本語能力試験3級(2024年7月)

・英語 : ビジネスレベル・ロシア語 : ビジネスレベル

・HackerRank - JavaScript (Intermediate) (2024年6月)

■自己PR

過去の仕事では、数々のアプリケーションの責任者として、クライアントの要件に合わせた高品質なソリューション を提供してきました。常に業界のトレンドや新興技術を把握することに注力し、クライアントのニーズに最適な解決 策を提供することを重視しています。

特にフロントエンド開発におけるプログラミングスキルにも自信があります。TypeScript や JavaScript などのプログラミング言語に精通しています。さらに、日本語の学習に積極的に取り組んでおり、それを続けています。また、いくつかのプロジェクトでフロントエンドチームリーダーとしてのマネジメント経験もあります。

自身の今までの経験を活かし、エンジニアリングおよびマネジメントに関する知識を深めながら、貴社の発展に貢献 したいと考えております。